没人能料到
You never know
在白驹过隙般的光阴流逝中
the biggest day of your life
某一天会成就为生命中最重要的日子
Is going to be the biggest.
而满心期盼翘首以待的那一天
The days you think are going to be big ones...
却往往会与你擦肩而过
They're never as big
从此彻底改变你心中已经勾画好的蓝图
As you make them out to be in your head.
也许  只是普通的日子
It's... the regular days...
那一天
The ones that...
以平凡开始
Start out normal...
却以完美的惊喜落幕
Those are the days that end up being the biggest.
今天  那个惊喜就是那个婚礼
And today was the wedding.
它是如此的美丽  摧枯拉朽般的完美
It was beautiful... Perfect.
只是平凡的一天
Just a normal day.
平凡的一天
A normal day.
我们还要开工
We're going to work.
这平凡的一天
Just a normal day
会以教堂婚礼而结束
that ends in a ceremony in a churchy church.
这些都是身外之事与我们无关
This has nothing to do with us.
你和我只是新娘和新郎
We're just the bride and groom.
今晚我们结婚了
We're getting married tonight.
你在这睡觉
You slept here?
我醒来了  出什么事了
I'm awake. what?
你睡在这里  我也睡在这里
You slept here? i slept here.
怎么回事  等下  谁  怎么了
Uh, how? wait, who, what?
我睡在了值班室
I slept in the on-call room.
哦
Oh.
我不能回家睡在自己的床上
I could've been at home in my own bed.
我对不起你
Sorry.
现在开始还要工作整整一天
Now i have to work all day,
晚上还要强装笑颜当个快乐的伴娘
And then i have to be happy maid of honor
然后陪着梅瑞狄斯走向圣坛
And get meredith down the aisle.
我累死了  就因为睡在这个鬼地方
I'm so tired... because i slept here,
因为你想和你的溜冰女孩共赴巫山
Because you wanted to get your freak on With roller skate girl.
我道歉
I am sorry.
我是那么打算来着  可是
I was gonna, but...
我们一起吃了晚饭  然后事情就
We went to dinner and... things didn't...
总之就是我没心情了
I wasn't in the mood.
我必须早点到医院主持急救室  所以
I had to be here early anyway to run the E.R., so...
你现在负责额外的急救室的轮班吗
Oh, you're--you're picking up extra shifts in the ER.
就是说  欧文今天没来
So is, uh, is Owen not here today?
他在这里  该死的  我迟到了
Oh, he's here. oh, crap. I'm late.
好日子啊  今天是你的好日子
Big day. biggest day of your life.
打住  别像个打了鸡血的伴娘
Don't do that. Don't do the peppy maid of honor thing.
太恐怖了
It's creepy.
真的啊  了解
Really? Good.
等等  这就是传说中黎明前的黑暗吗
Wait, is this, like, the calm before the storm?
要不要给你来点精神类药物
Do you need me to drug you
或者把你眉毛剃干净
Or shave off your eyebrows
彻底打消你当落跑新娘的念头
to numb you into submiss.
省省吧  我挺好的
No I am fine.
今天不是我的什么好日子
It's not the biggest day of my life.
是伊兹的好日子才对
It's the biggest day of izzie's life.
我期待的是即将开始的婚姻生活
I'm excited about the marriage,
不是什么结婚仪式
not some wedding.
总之  伊兹才得了新娘狂热症候群
Anyway, she's the one who's gone all bridezilla.
新娘狂热症候群
Bridezilla.
你绝对要好好看看那伴娘礼服
You should see the bridesmaids' dresses.
那些美丽的花  应该在五点送到这里
The flowers. They are gonne being deliever here at 5.
我付给他们额外的钱装饰了教堂
I had to pay extra for them to decorate the church,
不过德里克早就把信用卡交给我
But derek gave me his credit card,
让我全权负责  该买什么决不手软
Told me to do what i had to do,
所以一切都将完美无比
So... it's gonna be perfect.
-她血压怎么样  -在正常范围内
- How's her blood pressure?  - Within normal limits.
切口愈合的如何
And her incision site?
如我们术后两周预料的一样
Uh, as we expected two week after the surgey.
38小时前她刚注射白介素2
Well, she just got off I.L.-2.38 hours ago.
我的意思是她可能还
I mean she could still have
她的转移灶切除了  她的血压也正常
Her mets is gone, her blood pressure is fine
她的伤口一点都不疼
Her incision doesn't hurt.
她恢复的很好
She's doing well.
今天是婚礼日  我要去参加婚礼
It's wedding day, and i am going to the wedding.
我是新娘的傧相  我一定要去  对吧贝利
I'm a bridesmaid. i'm going. right, Bailey?
要我说你可以去
I said you could go.
结婚日  阿历克斯击掌庆贺
Wedding day! up top, alex.
我晚点再过来看你
I'll check on you later.
贝利  你别让我的手悬在这
Come on. don't leave me hanging, bailey.
婚礼日哦
Wedding day.
婚礼日
你是因为我有癌症才配合的
You just did that 'cause i have cancer.
-其实你根本不想配合我  -答对了
- You didn't mean it. - true.
我开始脱发了
My hair is starting to fall out.
你的美丽丝毫没有减少
You still look good.
我知道这意味着什么
I know what this means,
你的出现
You being here.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不过我还是要去参加婚礼
I'm still going to the wedding.
伊兹怎么样了
How's izzie?
-挺好的  -血压稳定吗
- Good.  - Is her B.P. stable?
如果血压过低的话  真的不可以去婚礼
If she's hypotensive, she really shouldn't go to the wedding.
-让我一个人为她操心吧  -好吧
- You let me worry about Izzie.  -All right.
你有什么病人给我们吗  有好病例吗
Do you have anything for us? Anything good?
木有  天下太平
Nope, it's slow.
在急诊室不可以这么说
You don't say it's a slow day in the pit.
绝对不可以这么说  你已经触了霉头
You never say it's slow. You just jinxed us.
普通一天  天下太平
It's a day and it's slow.
等电话一响  有伤者送到这里
When that phone starts ring and gets trauma
你就知道饭能乱吃  话不能乱讲
You're gonna wish you hadn't said that.
电话根本不会响
That phone never get ring.
今天天下太平
It's a slow day.
这里是西雅图圣恩医院急救室
Go for seattle grace emergency.
-我去穿急救服  -该死的  该死的  伤者马上就到
- I'll get the trauma gowns.  - Crap, crap. Incoming!
你的心理医生有什么进展吗
How's it going with your shrink?
我已经有些进步了
Um, i'm doing better...
要循序渐进
Inch by inch.
进展不快
Progress is... slow.
是你的吊扇  吊在你床上那个
It was your ceiling fan, above your bed--
扇叶转的就像直升飞机的扇叶
The blades spinning like the blades of a chopper.
心理医生说也许是那个刺激了我
Um, my shrink said that was the trigger to me
让我扼住了你的脖子
Choking you.
哦
Oh.
我看我们该分头去工作了
You know, we should probably get going.
大卫 赛盟斯  22岁  坐在驾驶席位
David Simons, 22. he was in the driver's seat.
他的车被一辆卡车撞到  一个轮胎爆了
His car got crushed by a semi truck blew a tire
被撞的车子又与四辆车连环相撞
And jackknifed across four lanes of traffic.
带他去一号急救室准备手术
Okay, take him to bay one until the trauma ready.
-伤者情况如何  -持续性的胸骨挫伤
- What are the injuries?  - He sustained chest contusions.
生命体征还算稳定
otherwise, vital stable
-我们不能迟到  -数一二三
- We can't be late.   - Ready? one, two, three.
-我们不能迟到  -什么迟到
- We can't be late.  - Late for what?
-毕业典礼  -Becca Wells
- Graduation.  - Becca Wells,
21岁  生命体征不稳
21-year-old.  Restrained vitals stable.
间歇性呼吸停猝  但是呼吸声音正常
Some shortness of breath, but good breath sounds.
好的  带她去二号抢救室
Okay, take her to bay two for now.
-我父亲在这  他会很担心的  -大卫  是你吗
- My dad's here. He's gonna be so worried.  - David, is that you?
-贝卡  是你吗  -我想是吧  我不确定
- Becca, are you okay?  - I-I think so. I don't know.
-三,  一二三  -你怎么样
-Three, One, two, three.  - How about you?
还能讲话
I'm talking.
-能讲话就说明还好  对吧  -对
- It can't be too bad if i'm talking, right? - Right.
22岁  坐在副驾驶位置
22-year-old front seat passenger.
盆骨压伤  血压不稳  微弱但是可见
Tenderness above the pelvis and unstable b.p. In the field.
好的  五号抢救室
Uh, bay five.
是我女朋友吗  她在后排坐着
Is my girlfriend here? She was in the back seat
-乔丹  -贝卡  你看见达纳了吗
- Jordan! -Becca? Becca, have you seen Dana?
你和她挨着坐的
You were sitting next to her.
你和其他朋友确认下吧
Can you check on the other friends.
达纳 米歇尔还有皮特
Dana, M-Michelle and Pete?
一共八个人困在SUV车里了
Eight of them piled in an S.U.V.?
他们几个情况都这么糟糕吗
A-are they all this bad?
这几个还算是好的
These are the healthy ones than others on the rest.
好吧  我需要床位  血浆还有实习生
Okay, uh, I need, uh, beds and blood and interns,
还有欧文亨特  他去哪里了
And--and Owen Hunt. where is Hunt?
室颤  血压下降
V-tach. b.p.'s dropped out.
我需要急救车  进行心率复苏
I need the crash cart. i'm gonna cardiovert.
-大卫他怎么了  -充电100伏  离手
David! what's wrong with him? Charge to 100. clear.
大卫  贝卡他怎么了
David! becca, what's wrong with david?
请你们一定要救活他  不能让他死
You have to save him, please. you can't let him die.
不可以是今天  今天是我们大学毕业的日子
Not today. we're supposed to be graduating from college.
-充电200伏  离手  -贝卡出什么事了
- Okay, charge to 200. clear.  - Becca, Becca, what's going on?
今天本来是我们的好日子
This is the biggest day of our lives.
亨特人死到哪里去了!
where in the hell is Hunt
谢谢老天  亨特
Oh, Hunt, thank god.
一到三号急救室
Uh, trauma one through three.
伤者情况如何
What do we got?
贝卡 威尔斯  呼吸频率20
Becca Wells-- respiratory rate of 20,
生命体征稳定
But otherwise, vital signs are stable.
大卫还好吗  他今天一定要毕业
Is--is David okay? he has to graduate today.
他是家中头一个上大学的人
He's--he's the first person in his family to go to college.
你现在不要担心你的朋友
Don't worry about your friends right now.
我们会照顾好他们的  没有血胸没有气胸
We'll take good care of 'em. No hemothorax or pneumothorax.
-已经准备照CT  -还要做一下X光检查
-In line for c.t.  - We're gonna do a few x-rays,
我要会想最好的办法治疗你的
Get a better idea of what's going on with you.
你的身体受到了很强的撞击
Your body's in some serious shock
我今天要做一个演讲的
I have a speech to give.
我必须  我本来应该  今天我要做毕业致辞
I have I'm supposed to... I'm valedictorian.
我在学校还从来没做过致辞
All i've ever done is school.
这是唯一的  也是最后的一次
It's all I've ever done.
直到今天为止
I haven't done anything else...
还有许多事情我都没做过
U-until today.
今天本来是我们生活新的开始
Today's the day that my life is supposed to start,
这就是为什么我一定要活下去  对吧
Which is why i'd really like to live, okay?
把CT结果告诉我
Let me know the results of the c.t. okay.
我还没看见达纳  她是我女朋友
I haven't seen Dana yet-- my girlfriend.
她坐在后排和米歇尔在一起
She was in the backseat next to Michelle--
输血  补充葡萄糖
Hang blood and push fluids.
她在跟着收音机一起唱歌
She was singing to the radio.
她总是不知道歌词是什么
She never knows the words to anything.
等我转身告诉她的时候
I turned around to tell her the words and then...
她已经不再那里了
She wasn't there anymore.
我们需要你平静下来  这样才能治疗你
We need youto calm down so we can tread you
你受了很严重的伤
You have very serious injuries.
她已经不在车里了
She was not in the car any more
我向你保证  只要我一有时间就帮你找她
I promise i will check for you as soon as i can,
但是你现在要保持平静配合治疗
But you need to stay still for me.
她穿了一件粉色的毛衣
she's wearing a pink sweater.
-好的  -继续抢救
- Okay.  - Keep working.
在你把他送到其他地方前  让他的血压上升
Try to get his pressure up before you move him anywhere.
心脏收缩稳定
Systolic and stabilizing,
但是有多重的心律不齐
But he's still having multiple arrhythmias.
我打算注射强心剂
I'm thinking cardiac contusion.
插呼吸管
I'm about to do chest too
欧麦利  这个病人你负责了
You've got this, O'malley.
-我拿到血浆了  -放进这个加速注射器
- I've got blood.  - Put it in the rapid infuser.
我的朋友都在这里吗  你看见皮特没
Are my friends here? Did you see Pete?
皮特是哪个
Which one's Pete?
他穿了红色运动鞋
He's wearing red sneakers.
还有米歇尔  她为了毕业典礼把头发染成蓝色
And Michelle--she dyed her hair blue for graduation.
你看见她了吗  她没事吧
Did you see her? Is she okay?
我去找找他们
Um, i-i'll find 'em.
我全家都来了
My whole family's coming.
我明白  今天是大日子
I know. It's a big day.
今天全是为了他们  今天是送给他们的礼物
For them. Today is for them.
室颤  他有危险  给我电击板
V-fib. He's coding. Get the paddles.
你呼我了
You paged me?
是的  你收到酒席承包人的最后确认没
Yes. did you get the check for the caterers
-给招待们现金小费  -是的
- And the cash tips for the waiters?  - Yes.
你写誓词了吗
Uh, did you write your vows?
-没呢  会写的  -德里克  你一定要写誓词
- Not yet. i will.  - Derek... you have to write your vows.
你今天在婚礼上你要和梅瑞狄斯说的  很重要的
What you say to meredith on this day, it's important.
她这辈子都不会忘记你今天的誓词
She'll remember it for the rest of her life.
伊兹
Izzie,
你呼我就为了讨论婚礼的事
So if you paged me to talk about the wedding,
我  并不是因为这个呼你的
I-- that's not why I paged you.
我还有一个开颅手术
I have a craniotomy to get to.
他回来了
He's back.
丹尼  回来了
Denny--he's back.
我呼贝利医生  我们安排你做
I'll page Dr. Bailey, and we'll order--
做一个核磁共振  我知道过程
Order an M.R.I. I know the drill.
你要见我  主任
You wanted to see me, chief?
德里克  本来要做这个的
Derek was supposed to do this,
但是他好像被什么事情拖住了
But he got pulled into something,
-所以我打算把这个给你  -什么
- So i said i'd give it to you.  - what?
你的结婚礼物  不是我送的  是德里克送的
Your wedding present. not from me. it's from derek.
但是我要监督全过程
But i have to oversee it.
-哪门子什么礼物  -梅瑞狄斯  这是
- I was supposed to get my present?  - Meredith, it's--
所以说婚礼真是愚蠢至极
This is why weddings are so stupid.
我们一生相守才该是礼物
I mean, our life together should be the present,
而不是什么愚蠢的  不管是什么  主任
Not some stupid--anyway, whatever it is, chief,
我不想要
I don't want it.
请告诉德里克让他拿回去  算了我跟他说
So tell Derek to take it back. Well, i'll tell him.
-我跟他说让他拿回去  -他要给你结肠
-I'll tell him to take it back.  - He got you a colon.
-什么  -结肠手术  不可返还  有炎症
- What?  - A colon. It's nonrefundable, it's inflamed,
在2号手术室里面临贫血
It's about to go under anesthesia in o.r. two.
你真的不想要吗
You really want to say you don't want it?
一个独立手术
A solo surgery?
恭喜结婚  梅瑞狄斯
Happy wedding day, Meredith.
有还是没有
Yes or no? Hey.
我不要"可能"  我要有或者没有
I don't need a maybe. I need a yes or a no.
那行  我就在这等着
Oh, okay. I'll be right here waiting.
你觉得谢博德和格蕾会长久吗
You think Shepherd and Grey are gonna last?
比如  50年
Like, uh, 50 years last?
一辆铰接货车撞了一堆学生
A semi crashed into a bunch of college kids
恰恰在我临时调班到急诊室的今天
On the day that I decided to take an extra shift in the e.r.
太好了  谢谢你
Oh! Great. Thank you.
全是烧伤  截肢
There's burns, digit amputations,
令人作呕的狰狞表情
Nasty, nasty facial lacerations,
-所以拜托别走开  好吗  -放轻松
- So please don't go anywhere, okay?  - Relax.
-你发誓  -你能搞定
- You promise?  - You're handling this.
我搞...  喂  你不能把他放这
I am handling-- hey! You-- you can't put him here.
医生要经过的
I've got doctors who need access.
昨晚怎么了
What went wrong last night?
我很忙  爱丽桑那
Uh, I'm kinda busy here, Arizona.
我有四个连续手术
I have four surgeries back to back
还有个孩子在靠机器维持生命  我也很忙
And a kid on life support-- I'm kinda busy, too.
-出什么事了  -那也不行
- What went wrong?  - Hey, that's not any better.
把他放在门厅
Put him in the hall.
我们一起去了西雅图最好的四星级酒店
We went out to a four-star restaurant, best in seattle.
本该是愉快浪漫的
It was supposed to be fun, romantic,
但你明知他们最拿手法国菜
But then you ordered a salad when they make
却点了份沙拉
The most delicious French food,
然后五指并用地狼吞虎咽  几乎没说话
And then you picked at it, barely spoke to me, then bolted.
到底怎么了  我做错了什么吗
So what went wrong? I mean, did-- did I do something?
我只是没心情  我当时筋疲力尽
I just wasn't feeling it. I was exhausted, tired.
对不起  我说的是门厅
Sorry. Hey! I said the hall.
门厅
The hall.
进度如何  欧麦利
Fill me in, O'malley.
我放进第一胸管  但没有血
I put in the first chest tube, but there's no blood
另外一个则没有脉搏
Tried another one, but there's no pulse.
这样多久了
How long has it been though
20分钟  要我打开他胸腔吗
20 minutes. Should I open his chest?
他死了  欧麦利  放手
He's gone, O'malley. Move on.
他今天就毕业了  今天就毕业了
He's supposed to graduate. To see him graduate.
欧麦利  放手  他死了  你救不了他
O'malley, let it go. He is gone. You can't save him.
你得去救你能救的人
You move on to save the people you can. mm-hmm.
还有很多伤者  欧麦利  动起来
We have more trauma coming in. O'malley, now. move.
报时  格蕾
Call it, Grey.
死亡时间  9点24
Time of death, 9:24.
什么可能都有
It could be anything.
甚至可能是纱布
It could be scar tissue, okay?
我们得等结果
We just wait and see
-是肿瘤  -别乱说
- It's tumor.  - You don't know that.
丹尼·杜奎特就站在你身后
Denny Duquette is standing right behind you.
是肿瘤  对吗丹尼
It's a tumor. Right, denny?
对
Yeah.
很高兴看到你  贝利医生
It's good to see you, Dr. Bailey.
你看不到他因为你没长肿瘤
You can't see him because you don't have a tumor,
他跟你问好
But he says hi.
告诉丹尼·杜奎特我叫他回老家
Tell Denny Duquette I said go home.
是肿瘤
It's a tumor.
看结果
Wait and see.
对不起  我哭得一反常态
I'm sorry. I'm crying more than usual.
你说是因为我受到惊吓  是吗
You said i'm in shock. Is that it?
对  也可能因为吗啡
Yeah. It's also the morphine.
我应该和大卫上床的
I should've slept with David.
我想到过的
I thought about it,
但他那么贴心  有趣
But he was... sweet and--and funny and...
我会爱上他的
I would've fallen in love with him.
但毕业前我不想恋爱
And I didn't want a relationship till after school. I...
我不喜欢半途而废
I don't like to do things... halfway.
我得先上学  再考虑生活
I was doing school, and then I was gonna do life.
而现在  大卫死了  死了
And now... now david's dead. David's dead.
片子怎么样  克莱夫
How was the c.t., karev?
由于横膈膜里的胶体
Her stomach is herniating into her left hemithorax
她的胃正破裂进左半胸
From a huge lac in her diaphragm.
好吧  贝卡  我们马上带你去做手术
Okay. Becca, we're taking you to surgery soon.
我应该
I should've...
我应该在还来得及的时候和大卫上床的
I should've had sex with David when I had the chance.
达纳还好吗
Dana... Is she okay?
护理人员还没领她进来
The paramedics haven't brought her in yet,
他们一来我会立即通知你
But as soon as they do, i'll let you know.
你有什么联系得到的家人吗
Do you have any, uh, family we can contact?
都在阿根廷
They're in Argentina.
我本来明天要飞去的
I'm supposed to fly there tomorrow.
这是分日
It's d-day.
是什么
It's what?
达纳取的名字
That's what Dana calls it.
我父母没钱供我留在这了
My parents don't have the money to let me stay.
我得回去
I have to go back.
我们都知道分日就要到了
We both knew d-day was coming.
我试过和她分手  这样轻松点
I tried to break up with her to make it easier.
我每学期换课
I'd switch classes every semester
确保我们不在一起上课
So that we didn't have any together.
但没用
But it didn't matter.
我离不开她
I couldn't stay away.
当你爱着一个人  你就拿爱情没办法
When you love someone, you know, love is love.
即使你们注定无法相守也无怨无悔
It doesn't matter that you're not supposed to be together.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
稳定下来了
Uh, he's starting to stabilize.
很好  看样子能拍片了
Good. Looks like he's ready for c.t.
我想  大概她已经放开了
I think... maybe she got out in time.
也许她没被伤那么深
Maybe she's not hurt that bad.
因为我回头的时候
Because when i turned around...
她已经不在了
She wasn't there.
她不在了
She was not there anymore.
X光可以用了
Okay, x-ray is really backed up,
-但  那个  那是皮特  -什么
- But... hey, that-- that's Pete.  - What?
大卫的朋友  皮特  红球鞋
David's friend--pete. The--the red sneakers.
你能过来帮我一下吗
Could you get over here and help me?
他胸口的血滴透衣服了
He's bleeding through the dressing on the chest wound.
脉搏220
Pulse is 220.
心囊流出
Pericardial effusion.
给我注射器和尖针头
Get me a syringe and a spinal needle.
给你
Here you go.
我要插进伤口
I'm going in through the wound.
再给我个注射器
Okay, I'm gonna need another syringe, now.
-血太多了  -注射器再来
- There's too much blood.  - Okay, just keep the syringes coming.
这次要60cc的
Give me a 60cc this time.
心脏停搏  他快不行了
Asystole. He's flatlining.
给我心电图板
Uh, get the cardio board. there. Just...
调高压力
Keep holding pressure.
听着我的指令把他转过来  123
Okay, i'm starting compressions on my count. One two three.
乔治
George.
调高压力  我不能让这个也去了
Just keeping putting pressure. I am not losing another one.
谢谢
Thank you.
你也在消毒吗  我以为是我独立完成
You're scrubbing in? I thought I was doing this solo.
-是的  -那你为什么不找个
- Oh, you are.  - Then why aren't you sitting
角落坐着看杂志
in a corner reading a magazine?
今天是大日子  梅瑞狄斯
Oh, this is a big day, Meredith.
我得作点预防措施  仅此而已
I'm just taking precautions, that's all.
你怕我在结婚的日子杀了我的病人
Afraid i'm gonna kill the patient on my wedding day?
这是常规结肠切除手术  我不会杀了他的
It's a routine colectomy. I'm not gonna kill him.
我知道  你会做得很好的
I-I know. You're gonna do great.
-就当我不在这  -好吧
- Pretend I'm not even here.  - Okay.
好了  包琪  解剖刀
Okay, boki... scalpel.
不错  漂亮
Oh, great. Very nice.
什么
What?
你要解剖刀的口吻
The way you asked for the scalpel.
你没有含糊  口齿清晰下达命令
You didn't mumble. You took charge right off the bat.
大声而清楚  "解剖刀"
Loud and clear--"scalpel."
很好  淋漓尽致
It was good. Very impressive.
好
Great.
我这就要开始了
I'm gonna get started now, s--
当然当然
Oh, of--of course.
你不会感觉到我在这的
You won't even know I'm here.
-谢谢  -也许我会干杯庆贺
-Thanks. -Maybe I'll toast to the fact
他们真心相爱
That they love each other
但这无法说明以后的事
It doesn't bring up the future.
这无法说明他们能否长久
It doesn't talk about whether they'll make it.
这也不错  对吗
It's good, right? mm-hmm.
你说你筋疲力尽
You said you were tired, exhausted,
但你不可能筋疲力尽  因为休息日
But you can't be that exhausted if you're working
-你还在急诊室加班  -我恢复了
-  in e.r. on your day off.  - I rallied.
-你恢复了  -没错
- You rallied?  - Yeah.
-撒谎  -没有  我没撒谎  我爱急诊室
- You're lying.  - No, I'm not lying. I love the e.r.
等会好吗  谢谢
Can you hold, please? Thanks.
-你爱急诊室  -对  乐此不疲
- You love the e.r.?  - Mm-hmm. Can't get enough of it.
太有趣了
It's fun.
你得告诉她
You should tell her.
对  住嘴  马克
Yeah. suck it, Mark.
外伤二科需要血源  快
Hey, we need more blood in trauma two. Go.
-亨特医生  -怎么了
- Dr. Hunt.  - What?
又死了一个  我的病人快死光了
I just lost another one. All my patients are dying.
我需要你帮助
I need you to help me.
这不是我能决定的  救护车又来了
That's not for me to decide. The ambulance is coming in.
-去看看你能做些什么  -我无能为力了
- Go see what you can do.  - I'm in over my head.
走开  欧麦利
Walk away, O'malley.
那是米歇尔  她为毕业染了发
That's Michelle. she dyed her hair for graduation.
看看
Look.
我在看  但什么都没看到
I'm looking, but I don't see anything.
因为什么都没有
Because there's nothing there.
-片子显示一切正常  -我告诉过你
- The scan's clean.  - I told you.
那为什么丹尼回来了  那是我的幻觉
Then why is Denny back? The man's a hallucination.
这说明我肯定长了点什么
That means there has to be something there.
听着伊兹  如果正常  那么
Look, Izzie, i-if it's clear, then...
我想去婚礼
I want to go to this wedding.
我想看着新娘走过长廊
I want to watch the bride walk down the aisle.
我想听到誓言  我想抓到花束
I want to hear the vows. I want to catch the bouquet.
我安排好了婚礼的每个细节
I planned this wedding down to the very last detail.
它完美无瑕
It's the perfect wedding.
这婚礼  完美无瑕
This wedding... is perfect.
你知道我有多想去
You know how much I want to be there.
那我为什么还要跟你说丹尼
So why would I tell you about Denny,
干嘛非得今天  我干嘛不再等等
Today of all days? Why wouldn't I just wait?
丹尼回来了
Denny is back.
说明有东西在里面
That means something is there.
我们不能因为幻觉
Well, it's not like we can just...
勾画大脑  这不像占领阵地那么简单
Map the brain for hallucinations the way we do a seizure.
等等  幻觉怎么来的
Wait a minute. What are hallucinations?
幻觉是大脑中闪动的神经细胞
Hallucinations are neurons firing in the brain.
没错
Exactly.
干嘛问这个
Why?
以前从没这么干过
Well, it's never been done before,
但如果我们想办法诱导出你的幻觉
But if we can somehow induce your hallucination,
我们就有可能通过录像脑电图选出它
There's a chance that we could pick it up on an e.e.g.
精确标出它在大脑里的位置
Then we could pinpoint the part of the brain
标出幻觉产生部位
That's hallucinating.
外伤一科
Uh, trauma one's open.
什么情况
What do we have?
她在野外时有脉搏
She had a pulse in the field,
但在过去30分钟里没再有过
But we haven't been able to get one now for over 30 minutes.
我确定她还有一半以上血
I'm pretty sure we left half her blood volume
在路边
On the side of the road.
她已经脑死亡  我需要你们来宣布死亡时间
She's d.o.a., man. i just need you to call it.
天啊  天啊
oh, god  oh my god
该死的  粉红毛衣  这是乔丹的女朋友
Crap. a pink sweater. that's jordan's girlfriend.
把她推离这里
Um, move her out of here.
宣布死亡时间
i need you to call it.
死亡时间
Time of death
丹娜  不要啊
dana! dana, no!
丹娜  我要见她
Dana, no, no, i need to see her!
来人啊
someone help me
死亡时间10点45分
time to death 10:45.
他昏迷了  把他移上急救车
He's coding. get a crash cart.
不  不  不不
No. no, no, no.
我们缝合伤口
We are closed to trauma.
因为我们有太多该死的伤口
Because we have trauma coming out of our butts.
也祝你今天过得很愉快
Oh, well, you have a nice day, too.
为了爱  所以说手术室比我更吸引你咯
Oh, for the love of-- so the e.r. is fun, but i'm not?
艾利桑娜
Arizona--
你不能跟我聊太久
you can't get enough of me?
你是不是想这样跟我说
is that what you're saying
我的意思是你是不是想分手
I mean, do you just want to just end this?
因为  还有很多女人想泡我
Because--because there are women that are lining up for me.
我很辣  如果你想分手  你就应该
I'm hot, and if you want out, then you should just
勇敢地跟我说  我会接受的
Have the guts to say so. i can take it.
也许这就是我们的必然结局  好吗
Maybe this was just a fling that's run its course, okay?
也许我们该分手
Maybe it's over.
也许吧
maybe it is.
我发现这有些黏合
I got some adhesions.
我需要把它切开  令反曲流通
I need to dissect down to mobilize the sigmoid.
博维刀  谢谢
Bovie, please.
你有什么话要说吗
Do you have something you'd like to say?
不  没有  你做得很好
Oh, no, no. you're-- you're doing fine.
做主刀医生的感觉如何  格蕾
How's the solo surgery coming along, grey?
你问问主任就可以知道
Well, i think it's going okay,
我做得还不错
But you should probably ask the chief here.
她做得很好
Well... she's doing great.
她一开始选择了烧灼器
She chose a cautery when, at one point,
如果是我就会选择剪刀
I probably would've gone with scissors,
但是她成功了
But she made it work.
看来我们可以为婚礼争取到充足的时间
We'll be out of here In plenty of time for the wedding.
很好  那样他就没有借口了
good. then she won't be excuses
什么
Excuse me?
这是我第二次担任德里克的伴郎
this is the second  i've been derck's best friend
我得来确定
I have to come up with a toast,
跟你说一些人生道理  这是很有必要的
Offer some words of wisdom-- it's a lot of work.
我不想第三次做他的伴郎  如果你明白我意思的话
I don't want to have to be his best man a third time If you know what i mean.
所以说你来这是为了威胁我咯
so you came in here to threaten me?
我是他的伴郎  这是我的职责
I'm his best man. that's my job.
又怎么了
What now?
没有  不错  做的不错
Oh, no. it's okay. it's fine.
事情都做的不错  对吧
Everything-- everything's fine, right?
我不需要说什么啊
I-i don't need to say anything.
所以说  现在要干嘛
So... now what?
我只要出现幻觉就好了吗
I just try to have a hallucination?
是的
Yep. okay.
斯蒂文斯  都只有丹尼出现吗
Stevens, is it always denny?
我的意思是  都没有出现过其他人吗
I mean, no one else?
是的没有其他人出现过
yeah.
怎么了
what?
没  没什么
Oh, no, nothing.
我明白了  他是你的爱人
It makes sense. it's the man you love.
他不是我的爱人
He's not the man i love.
他不是吗
he's not?
我的意思是  我喜欢丹尼
Well, i mean, i... i love denny.
我一直都喜欢他  他是我很重要的一个人  我
I will always love denny. he means a lot to me. i...
但我觉得幻觉丹尼
But i think i hallucinate denny
是因为我死与濒死和他联想在一起
Because i associate him with death and dying.
当我想到我的将来  我现在这样子
When i think about my future-- who i am now,
我的理想  我要怎样过我剩下的人生
Who i want to be, how i want to spend the rest of my life,
当你心情激荡的时候
When you get that flutter in your chest--
阿历克斯  阿历克斯是我的爱人
Alex. alex is the man i love.
克莱夫
Karev.
我爱阿历克斯·克莱夫
I love alex karev.
那  让我们找到肿瘤并把它拿出来吧
So... let's find this tumor and get it out of me
那样我们就可以去办我们的完美婚礼了
So that we can have our perfect wedding--
那个男女主角都不
A wedding not wasted on two people
太重视的婚礼
Who don't appreciate weddings.
我听见了
I can hear you.
我知道你听见了
i know you can hear me.
我就是要你听见
i mean for you hear me
如果我不能让他出现怎么办
What if i can't make him appear?
我们会一直等
we'll wait unt
你2个小时内要到教堂准备
Well, you have to be at the church in two hours.
这要花起码2个小时
It could take more than two hours.
我可以迟一点的
i'll be late.
不  不  不要迟到
No. no, no being late.
我会让他出现的  我可以的
I'll make him appear. i can do this.
来吧  丹尼
Come on, denny.
我朋友们怎么了
H-how are my friends doing?
告诉我吧
Just tell me.
我承受得了的
I can take it.
其实是承受不了的  但我必须承受
I mean, i can't, but i can.
有人离开了吗
Did someone else die?
为什么你不告诉我你的演讲词
Why don't you tell me your speech?
你的毕业演讲
Your graduation speech.
我承受得住的
I can take it.
跟我讲一下你的演讲词吧  贝卡
Becca, just... just give me your speech.
你为它努力了
You worked hard on it.
你现在就该讲出来
You should do it right now.
来吧
Come on.
今天是我生命的起始日
Today is the day my life begins.
今天
Today...
我成为了世界公民
I become a citizen of the world.
今天我是成年人
Today i become a grown-up.
从今天起我要为我的行为负责
Today i become accountable
不仅仅为我自己和我的家人
To someone other than myself and my parents...
为他人服务
Accountable for more than my grades.
从今天起我要为世界服务
Today i become accountable to the world...
为了将来
To the future...
为生活所经历的
To all the possibilities that life has to offer.
都从今天开始
Starting today...
来吧  丹尼  来吧
Come on, denny. come on.
我的使命是  挺身而出
My job is to show up...
扩大视野
Wide-eyed...
我们是自愿
And willing
且已经准备好了的
And ready.
为了什么
For what?
我也不清楚
I don't know.
为任何事情
For anything...
为一切的事情
For everything...
该死的  调到360
Damn it. charge to 360.
去承受生活
To take on life...
做得很好  梅瑞狄斯
Nice job, meredith.
去承受爱
To take on love...
当我不需要你的时候你偏偏在这
All the times i didn't ask for you, and you were here.
现在  我需要你  拜托
Now i'm asking.Please.
拜托你  出现在我面前  现在
please come to me now.
现在请你帮帮我  好吗
Please help me now. come on.
来吧  丹尼  现在让我看到你
Come on, denny. just--you come to me now.
丹尼
Denny.
去承受
To take on...
责任和可能
The responsibility and possibility.
今天  我的朋友都重生了
Today, my friends, are lives begin.
死亡时间  13点02分
Time of death--1302.
而我呢
And i, for one...
丹尼
Denny.
Denny!
在那
There.
已迫不及待了
Can't wait.
我来了  伊玆
i'm here for you, izzie.
就在那里
It's right there.
这就是泰斯勒磁共振的结果?
These the results of the tesla 7 m.r.i.?
是的  你看看那部分
Yeah. you know that part of the brain
就是它导致幻觉的出现
That reacted during the hallucination
这是另一个颞叶
It was the other temporal lobe.
那
That...
那就是肿瘤
That's the tumor?
是的  很小
Yeah. tiny.
小到连磁共振都查不出来
Too small to pick up on a normal m.r.i.
但是  好吧  如果那么小的话
But... o-okay, if it's that small,
你打算怎么把它拿出来呢
How are you gonna get to it?
我希望我能为她做点事情
I wish there was something i could do for her.
我希望我能
I wish i could...
我喜欢斯蒂文斯
I like stevens.
她是好人中的好人
She's one of the good ones.
我希望我能为她做点事情
I wish there was something i could do for her.
我
I, um...
我知道有件事你一定能做
I know something you can do.
我只是想让你知道我受伤了
I just want you to know that i'm hurt.
我受伤了而且我很生气
I am hurt and i am angry,
因为我认为我们之间还有感情的
Because i thought that we had something.
还以为我们会去某个地方
I thought that we were going somewhere.
如果你要在这睡觉
If you're just sleeping around,
如果你只想在围绕在众多女外科医生里
If you're just making the rounds of girl surgeons,
我想你必须要知道
Then i think that you ought to know
我们去了一家高级餐厅
that i-- we went to a fancy resturant
什么
What?
我们去了一家高级餐厅
we went to a fancy restaurant,
西雅图最漂亮的餐厅
The nicest restaurant in seattle.
那沙拉  我叫的那份沙拉  要26.95美金
The salad that i ordered-- the salad--cost $26.95.
你叫的那瓶酒要125美金
The wine that you ordered cost $125 a bottle.
我连主食都没有看
I didn't even look at the entrees
因为我吃不起
Because i knew i wasn't gonna be able to order one
因为我已经超出了75美元了
Because i was already out 75 bucks,
然而我根本不喜欢沙拉
And i don't even like salad. oh.
当付账的时候  你
And then the bill came, and you-
我  我付
i... i paid.
你知道当你
Do you know what i was doing
拿出支票的时候我在做什么吗
Before they brought over the check?
我当时在脑子里算
I was counting in my head trying to figure out
如果我有75美元的话
How i was gonna buy food for the rest of the week
接下来这几个星期我要怎么用它来解决吃饭问题
If my half was 75 bucks...
但是我没有75美元
Because i don't have 75 bucks
因为我爸不认我了
Because my father disowned me
他清空了我的银行存款
And has cleared out my bank account.
我破产了
I am broke.
凯丽
callie...
我已经筋疲力尽了  艾利桑娜
And i am exhausted, arizona.
我在医院工作  因为我需要钱
I'm working in the e.r. because i need the money.
我今天眼睁睁地看这六个人死
Six people died on my watch today,
我难受死了
And i am fried.
我昨天晚上很想留下来
I wanted to stay in last night.
我以为  我以为昨晚
I thought... i thought that last night
将会是我们的
Would be the night for us,
你知道的  我们的晚上
You know, our night.
但你要去那高级餐厅
But you wanted to go to a fancy restaurant,
我不能去
And i... i can't do that.
我不能
I can't.
好了  没事了  都过去了
Hey, it's okay. it's okay. hey.
我们留在医院
So... we stay in.
我们吃
And we'll eat...
三文治
Sandwiches.
你从不喜欢三文治啊
You don't even like sandwiches.
但是我喜欢的女生她喜欢三文治啊
But i like the girl who has the sandwiches.
这样可以吗
Okay?
可以
Okay.
但是  你知道吗
No, you know what?
其实我也不喜欢三文治  我喜欢披萨
I don't like sandwiches either. i like pizza.
我也喜欢披萨
I like pizza, too.
梅瑞狄斯
Meredith.
在  主任
Yes, sir.
我在看你妈的日记
I've been reading your mother's journals.
我希望她现在在这
I wish she was here today.
我不知道她对我
Well, i don't know How she would've
结婚这事是抱什么态度
felt about me getting married.
不是  不是为了那个  是这个
No, not for that. for this...
是为了你第一次主刀手术
Your first solo surgery.
这样啊  她也许会说
Oh, well, she probably would've said,
手术中可能会犯的错误你都犯了
With all the mistakes i've made,
我真庆幸病人还活着
I'm lucky the patient's alive.
讲得没错
yeah,that's right.
但我知道她会很激动
But i also know that she would've been thrilled.
虽然她不一定会告诉你
She wouldn't have been able to tell you,
但我知道她一定会很激动的
But she would've been.
谢谢你主任
Thank you, sir.
你  最好的结婚礼物
Hey. you-- best wedding present ever.
你知道为什么吗
And you know why?
不知道啊
No.
因为现在我要回家
Because now i have to go home
穿上紧身衣  丝袜  衬裙
And put on a corset and pantyhose and a petticoat
还得打扮得像个傻帽似的
And look like one of those idiots
比结婚蛋糕还傻帽
On top of a wedding cake,
我还得步入红毯
And then i have to walk down the aisle
被众人盯着看
And have everyone staring at me.
但没关系
But it's okay,
因为我今天从头到尾一个人完成了手术
because i got to cut someone open today from start to finish.
我救了一条命
I saved a life.
怎么
What?
不如我们让这一天再更有意义些
What do you say we make this day even better?
干得好  欧麦利
Good work today, o'malley.
干得好
Good work?
-他们死了  这些孩子都死了  -没全死
- They're dead. all those kids are dead. - not all of them.
的确  我没碰的那个就好好的
No, the one i didn't touch is just fine.
那是因为我及时救了她
yeah, because i was able to get to her.
而我能及时救她的唯一原因
And the reason i was-- the only reason--
是因为有你帮我
Is because i had you on my team.
救她一命  功劳有你的一半
You saved that girl today as much as i did.
外伤手术是团队战斗  欧麦利
Trauma's a team sport, o'malley.
你不必逞英雄  你只需...
You don't have to be the hero. you just...
你只需做好份内的工作
You just have to go where you're needed.
阿历克斯
Alex...
贝利说谢博德在她脑里又发现了肿瘤
Bailey says shepherd found another tumor in izzie's brain.
你听说了吗
Did you hear?
-是的  -我只是
- I heard. - i just--
-阿历克斯  -他认为这次没法取出
- Alex-- - he doesn't think he's gonna get it out this time.
我觉得
I think...
我觉得她会死在我面前
I think she's gonna die on me.
她真的会死
I think she's really gonna die.
你在这干嘛
Oh! what are you doing here?
你不是还要准备婚礼吗
Aren't you supposed to be getting ready for a wedding?
我来找你正是为此
Well, that's what i came to talk to you about.
你好  我是格蕾医生
Hi. i'm dr. grey.
我要处理你的中心线
I'm gonna take care of your central line.
好
Okay.
你哭了
You're crying.
因为你还活着
You're breathing.
我的鞋...  在那个橱里
My shoes are, uh, in the closet there.
-贝利  -鞋  知道了
- Bailey? - um, shoes, right.
说好的你来帮我  做准备
You're supposed to be helping me... get ready.
我还能去的  是吗
I can still go, right?
肿瘤又跑不了  所以
I mean, the tumor's not going anywhere, so...
当然能去
Yeah, you can go.
那好
Okay, well...
我们最好别迟到
We don't want to be late.
-贝利  -她来了
- Bailey-- - hey, oh, uh, here she comes.
梅  你现在该在教堂里
Mer! you're supposed to be at the church.
我马上就去  只是过来告诉你
I'm going. i just came to say,
这婚纱不是我的
this isn't my dress.
怎么不是你的  跟你配极了
Of course it's your dress. it's perfect.
你什么意思
It... what are you talking about?
不  这婚纱不该我穿
no, this dress is not for me.
我不明白  怎么回事
I don't... what?
我的天
Oh, god.
我就知道你会在婚礼前退缩
I knew you were gonna freak out before the wedding.
梅  德里克很爱你  结婚百利而无一害
Mer... derek loves you. marriage is good.
-你劝劝她  -不 她的意思是
-Tell her it's good.  -No, she's saying...
这婚纱不该她穿
it's not her wedding dress.
她说得对
She's right.
这婚纱不该梅瑞狄斯穿
The dress isn't for meredith.
梅
Oh, mer.
我不...
I don't...
我不知道说什么好
I-i don't even know how to...
我
I...
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了
Okay.
谁来做伴娘  我还是克里斯蒂娜
So who's the maid of honor, me or cristina?
克里斯蒂娜
Cristina.
阿历克斯需要伴郎
Alex--he needs a best man,
伴郎需要你  所以
And he was asking for you, so...
这么说  我是挑剩下的
Oh, so what, i'm-- i'm leftovers?
你尽力救我性命
you tried to save my life.
你绝对配当我的伴娘
That makes you honorable.
挽着我的手
Take my hand.
各位来宾
Dearly beloved,
今日我等共聚于此圣地
We are gathered here today to celebrate the wedding
庆祝亚历山大·迈克·克莱夫
Of alexander michael karev
与伊泽贝尔·凯瑟琳·斯蒂文斯的婚礼
And isobel catherine stevens.
婚礼是神圣的仪式
This is a sacred rite,
是古老的仪式
An ancient rite.
伊泽贝尔与阿历克斯即将携手
As isobel and alex prepare to join their lives,
希望大家能够理解  在座各位
It is important to understand that everyone present
都共同造就了他们的今日
Has played a part in shaping their lives
并将继续影响两人的未来
And will continue to play a vital role in their continuing future.
我们来此  不仅为见证他们之间的誓言
And thus,we are here not only to witness their vows to each other,
更为向他们赠予衷心的祝福
But to bestow upon them our blessing.
现在请新人宣读誓言
And now the couple will read their vows.
我们没准备过
Uh, we didn't write anything.
等等  我有话要说
No, wait. i have something i want to say.
今天  我步入了新的人生起点
Today's the day my life begins.
在此之前  我总是像个
All my life, i've been just me--
油嘴滑舌的孩子
Just a smart-mouth kid.
今天我成为了男人
Today i become a man.
我成为了丈夫
Today i become a husband.
今日起  我将对除我以外的人负责
Today i become accountable to someone other than myself.
我将对你负责
Today i become accountable to you,
对我们的未来负责
To our future,
对我们婚姻的一点一滴负责
To all the possibilities that our marriage has to offer.
只要你我齐心  无论未来如何
Together, no matter what happens,
我将时刻准备着
I'll be ready...
面对任何事
For anything...
面对每一件事
For everything...
承担生活
To take on life,
承担爱情
To take on love,
承担一切可能性及责任
To take on possibility and responsibility.
今天  伊兹·斯蒂文斯  我俩的生活开始了
Today, izzie stevens, our life together begins.
我已迫不及待
And i, for one, can't wait.
我爱你
I love you.
-没到时候  -请快些
- Not yet. - hurry up.
上帝及华盛顿政府赋予我权利
By the power vested in me by god and the state of washington,
我现在宣布  你们结为夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
可以了吗
Now?
请吧
Now.
你不会知道  生命里最重要的一天
You never know the biggest day of your life
就是那一天
Is the biggest day...
直到那天真正到来
Not until it's happening.
没关系
Hey. hey, it's okay.
不过是头发而已  你不需要
It's just hair. you don't need it.
最后都会掉光的
It's just gonna keep falling out.
那就剃掉好了
We'll shave it off.
我打赌你光头的样子也很美
I bet you look good bald anyway.
好吗
Okay?
别哭了
Stop.
你太美了
You're beautiful.
你不会发现那天就是生命里最重要的一天
You don't recognize the biggest day of your life,
直到那一刻真正到来
Not until you're right in the middle of it.
当你承担起责任
The day you commit to something or...
向某人许诺
Someone...
当你心碎的那一刻
The day you get your heart broken...
今天是婚礼日之外最美妙日子了
Best non-wedding day ever.
再来一次
Want to go again?
当你找到另一半
The day you meet your soul mate...
当你发现
The day you realize...
你的时日无多
There's not enough time...
因为你想要永生
Because you want to live forever...
这些才是最重要的日子
Those are the biggest days...
完美的日子
The perfect days...
你懂吗
You know?
你当新娘的样子一定美极了
I bet you made a beautiful bride.
那天真的很美
It was a beautiful day.
你把头巾戴上了
You put the scarf on.
我说了  你不必这样
I told you, you don't need it.
不戴头巾照样美若天仙
You look gorgeous without it.
他说得对
He's right.
你走吧
Go away now.
走吧
Go away.
我想单独待会儿
I want to be alone...
陪着我的丈夫
With my husband.
我老婆好正点
My wife is hot.